Here's an example.
我们来看如下的例子
Imagine your network is a stack of simple operations;
假设你的神经网络 是由一系列的简单运算构成
like linear transforms, ReLUs, whatever you want.
譬如线性变换、ReLu 等等
Some have parameters, like the matrix transforms,
有的变换有参数 如矩阵变换
some don't, like the ReLUs.
有的则没有 如 ReLu
When you apply your data to some input x,
当你把数据输入到 x
you have data flowing through the stack up to your predictions y.
它们将会经过这堆运算 然后得到预测值 y
To compute the derivatives,
为了计算相应的导数
you create another graph that looks like this.
我们又画出了新的图来演示如何运算
The data in that new graph flows backwards through the network,
新图中数据的流动方向 与之前相反
gets combined using the chain rule that we saw before, and produces gradients.
并通过我们刚刚演示的链式法则计算出梯度
That graph can be derived completely automatically
这个图 可以完全自动地从
from the individual operations in your network.
你神经网络中每一步的运算得出
So, most deep learning frameworks will just do it for you.
大多数深度学习框架 都会为我们完成这项工作
This is called back propagation and it's a very powerful concept.
这叫做反向传播 (Back-propagation) 是一个非常强大的概念
It makes computing derivatives of complex function very efficient,
当函数是由拥有简单导数的函数复合而成的时候
as long as the function is made up of simple blocks with simple derivatives.
该方法计算函数导数非常高效
Running the model up to the predictions is often called the forward prop.
运行该模型进行预测的过程一般被称为正向传播 (Forward Prop)
And the model that goes backwards is called the back prop.
而当模型反向运行以计算导数的时候 则被称为反向传播 (Backward Prop)
So to recap, to run stochastic gradient descent.
让我们来总结一下 在使用随机梯度下降法时
For every single little batch of your data in your training set,
对训练集中的每一小批数据
you're going to run the forward prop and then the back prop.
你要先进行正向传播 然后进行反向传播
And that will give you gradient for each of your weights in your model.
如此 你将会得出你模型各个权重的更新梯度值
Then you're going to apply those gradients with learning
然后 你就可以在原始的权重上
rates to your original weights and update them.
使用求出的梯度值和学习率来更新它
And you're going to repeat that all over again many, many times.
你将会重复该过程一次又一次
This is how your entire model gets optimized.
而这 就是你的模型如何得到优化的
I'm not going to go through more of the math of what's going on in each of those blocks,
我不准备展开讲 每一步运算背后的数学原理
because again you don't typically have to worry about that.
因为你通常不需要担心那些问题
And it's essentially the chain rule.
因为它的核心就是链式法则
But keep in mind this diagram.
不过你要记住这个图
In particular, each block of the back prop often takes
特别是反向传播中的每个区块
about twice the memory that's needed for the forward prop and twice to compute.
相比正向传播 它们通常需要花费两倍的算力与储存空间
That's important when you want to size your model and fit in memory for example.
当你的内存相对较小 需要控制模型尺寸时 这将非常重要